Hvderabad. India

🛘 (+91) 9182504755 | (+91) 9177896188 | 🗷 saitejdandge1@gmail.com | 🏕 saitejdandge1.wixsite.com/resume | 🖸 saitejdandge | 🛅 saitej-dandge-65046083

"The mark of true programmer lies in adapting to new technologies."

Summary.

Currently working in NCR Corporation as Software Engineer (Mobile Developer, Android & iOS), & III-H Certified Datascientist, Worked as Android Lead Developer in a startup Janaspandana Software Solutions, Hyderabad. Freelanced android application Stumagz, which made its place in Asia FORBES30. 3+ years experience in developing Android Applications and Web Development. Launched 3 android applications in play store and freelanced 3 android applications. Google Facilitator of CBIT, Hyderabad.Public Speaker.Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools for fun and adapting myself to new technical trends.

Education

Certification in Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence from IIIT-H

III-H, Hyderabad

III-H, HYDERABAD

Jan. 2018 - May. 2018

- Supervised, UnsupervisedLearning, Datapreprocessing, Data Visualizations, DeepLearning, NLP,...etc
- Certificate: https://goo.gl/xAgC5j

CBIT (Chaitanya Bharathi Institute of Technology)

Gandipet, Hyderabad

B.E. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

May. 2013 - May. 2017

• CGPA - 7.9/10.

Sri Gayatri Junior College

Madhapur, Hyderabad

INTERMEDIATE

May. 2011 - May. 2013

· Percentage - 97%.

Model High School

Suryapet

SECONDARY SCHOOL EDUCATION

- May. 2011

• Percentage - 92%.

Skills_

Basic Programming Languages

- C, C++, Java, Android, Objective C.
- Data Structures & Algorithms
- · Basics of Python.

Datascience and Machine Learning

- Machine learning in Python.
- Numpy, Scipy, Sklearn, Pandas, Matplotlib.
- Keras, Tensorflow for DeepLearning.

FrontEnd Development

- Web Development using HTML, CSS, Javascript, Angular2.
- Native Android development with JAVA, XML, Retrofit.
- Hybrid App development with React-Native.

BackEnd Development

- · SQL, No-SQL databases.
- · MongoDB, FirebaseDB.
- NodeJS, MEAN Stack.

Cloud & Other API's

- · REST API using Retrofit, AsyncTask, Threads.
- Firebase Cloud Messaging, Storage Bucket, Database, Dynamic Links, Invites.
- · Facebook, Google Login SDK, OAuth-2.0.
- Google Map API, Youtube Data API, Places API.
- · MongoDB.
- · Google Cloud Engine.
- · Amazon Web Services EC2, S3, Lambda, DynamoDb.

Work Experience _____

NCR CORPORATION NCR Corporation, Hyderabad

SOFTWARE ENGINEER AND MOBILE DEVELOPER

- Android and iOS native app development in NCR Corporation.
- Worked with 4 Projects (Android/iOS) in 5 months.
- Technologies: JAVA, Objective C, REST API, XML.

Google CBIT, Hyderabad

MAIN SPEAKER AND GOOGLE FACILITATOR FOR APPLIED CS WITH ANDROID PROGRAMME, CBIT

March. 2016 - May. 2017

July. 2017 - PRESENT

- Delivered workshops on Android Development, Data Structures, Algorithms to students in my campus in regard of this programme.
- Talked about latest trending topics like Firebase Cloud, AWS, Machine Learning(TensorFlow), Implementation of Data Structures in Android.
- More than 200 people participated in this programme. Workshop benefited students won 7 national rank in Smart Hackathon under supervision of Mr.Narendra Modi, Government of India.

Datascience

Object Recognition Image Classifier with machine learning.

Hyderabad

2018

DEVELOPER

DEVELOPER

• Trained model with supervision, that can recognize object from image.

- Dataset: The CIFAR-100 dataset consists of 60000, 32x32 colour images in 10 classes, with 6000 images per class. There are 50000 training images and 10000 test images.
- Classifier: Convolutionary Neural Network

Library: Keras Python Library.

Code: https://github.com/saitejdandge/21-Machine-Learning-Weeks/tree/master/object-recognizer

MNIST Handwritten Digits Classification.

Hyderabad

2018

- Trained model with supervision, that can recognize handwritten digit.
- Dataset: The dataset consists of 42000, 784 features each in 10 classes
- Dimensionality reduction using PCA to have perfect square dimension 784 —-> 625
 Reshaping linear data as 2 * 2 array [42000 (number of samples) ,25,25,1 (number of channesl)]
- Classifier: Convolutionary Neural Network

Library: Keras Python Library.

Problem Statement: https://www.kaggle.com/c/digit-recognizer

Code: https://github.com/saitejdandge/21-Machine-Learning-Weeks/tree/master/digit-recognizer

Chatbot for Library Management and Restaurant Finding.

Hyderabad

DEVELOPER

· Understands Intent from string and Performs Action specified.

 Database: CSV Files Platform: Python

• Code: https://github.com/saitejdandge/21-Machine-Learning-Weeks/tree/master/chatbot

Mobile Apps_____

Stumagz (Android Application, 10K Downloads @recognized in FORBES ASIA UNDER30)

Hyderabad

ANDROID DEVELOPER (FREELANCED PROJECT)

Jun. 2017 - July. 2017

- Implemented RESTful API client for student magazine application Stumagz.
- Material Design, Glide, GSON for Json parsing, Retrofit, AsynTask, Threading to make asynchronous network calls.
- Playstore Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.tdevelopers.stumagz.

May 21, 2018 SaiTej Dandge · Résumé

Questo (Android Application)

Hyderabad

FOUNDER & DEVELOPER 2017

- · Questo is crowd sourced application, in which an authenticated user can upload a MCQ or write a blog/feed with tags.
- Material Design, Authentication with Facebook login SDK in Android.
- · Push notifications with Firebase Cloud Messaging.
- Playstore Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.tdevelopers.questo

Track My Bus (Android Application)

Hyderabad

2016

FOUNDER & DEVELOPER

December - 2016

- This application is an effort to solve problem of tracking real time bus positions of my college and users get push notification when event occurs.
- Used serverless Architecture, Functions as a Service by AWS Lambda
- Technologies: Amazon DynamoDb, AWS Lambda, Google Map API, Google Places API.

Noter (Web Application)

Hyderabad

• Simple Web application built using Angular 2, Mongo DB, Firebase Hosting.

- · Built API using NodeJS to fetch data from MongoDB hosted in cloud. UI built using Angular material.
- Front End- Angular 2

Back End- Mongo Rest API calls (Reference: http://docs.mlab.com/data-api)

Database - Mongo DB

Hosting - Firebase Hosting.

- Live running at: https://noter-4e3e3.firebaseapp.com/notes
- Code: https://github.com/saitejdandge/Noter-MEAN-Stack

Hide My Text (Cryptic Tool in Android)

Hyderabad

2015

DEVELOPER

DEVELOPER

- This app provides secret messaging using poly-alphabetic cipher symmetric encryption which is unique for every pair of chat.
- PlayStore Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.tdevelopers.hidemyttext

Achievements & Awards

2016 Selected for Google Facilitator Programme, Applied CS with Android

Google, Hyderabad

Writing_

(Published) IEEE paper on Crowd Sourced Utility using Cloud

Hyderabad

Co-Author

2017

Drafted, demonstrated a way to use cloud technology in solving real time real time problem.
 Paper: http://www.ijarem.org/papers/v3-i7/16.IJAREM-B193.pdf

Program Committees

2016-17	Main Speaker, Applied CS with Android, Google	CBIT, Hyderabad
2016-17	Core Team Member, CBIT Information Security Club	CBIT, Hyderabad
2016-17	Formal In-charge, Google Student Club	CBIT, Hyderabad
2015-16	Organizer , C-Star Event, Sudhee Tech Fest	CBIT, Hyderabad
2015-	Active Participant, Google Developer Group	Hyderabad
present	Active Participant, Google Developer Group	riyaerabaa

May 21, 2018 SAITEJ DANDGE · RÉSUMÉ